riley.k.scheid@gmail.com

Riley Scheid

Software Developer | Product Maker

415 735-5151

github.com/sp33drac3r

Summary

In January of 2015, a co-worker at Google introduced me to Python. It wasn't long before I realized I had found my calling and, one year later, I left my job to learn to program full time. Since writing my first program (fizzbuzz), I have developed a deep fascination with computers and admiration for the people who speak their language fluently.

My greatest strength is my ability to learn quickly. I learned Python in 3 months, creating an internal tool that is still in use. In 6 months, I taught myself enough stats to transition from a support role to a quantitative business analyst position at Google.

Languages

Ruby, JavaScript, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS

Technologies

Rails, Sinatra, Grape, Node.js, RSpec, Rack, jQuery, AJAX, React.js, Sass, HAML, erb, React.native

Projects

- chelsie: chelsie is an anonymous online community for survivors of college sexual assault.
- chelsie.io: chelsie.io is a publicly available API that serves information about local rape crisis centers.
- mindgrapes: A cloud journaling platform that performs sentiment analysis on your entries to give you a visual representation of your mood over time.
- **Honey Mushroom**: A Ruby gem that builds and traverses common abstract data structures.

Experience

Google, Chromecast

Data Analyst

May 2014 - January 2016

- Found \$2,000,000+ operational expense savings in 2015 by consolidating vendors and underutilized programs.
- Owned user data pipeline beginning with customer support touch-points and ending with actionable insights for product and engineering.
- Wrote Python scripts to gather and analyze bugs and customer pain points.
- Forecast demand for Chromecast support to best serve the customer, ensured adequate staffing and optimized cost.

Google, YouTube

Support Specialist

July 2012 - May 2014

- Implemented support infrastructure tooling (CRM and call routing).
- Trained 200+ call center agents for product launch

LanguageTwin

Co-founder, Business Development Director

July 2011 - July 2012

- Managed \$100,000+ seed round with 5 investors, allowing for app redesign and product launch.
- Recruited 27 top universities for pilot program; used the resulting data to improve user experience and market positioning.

Education

Kenyon College BA Political Science '11

riley.works linkedin.com/in/rileyscheid